Register of the Germany Deutsche Kongress-Zentrale records
Hoover Institution Archives
Germany Deutsche Kongress-Zentrale Records
1870-1943
XX346
Hoover Institution Archives
381 manuscript boxes, 47 card file boxes, 17 phonorecord disk boxes, 3 binders, 1 envelope, 1 oversize folder (191 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, pamphlets, conference proceedings, clippings, and newspaper issues, relating to conferences of cultural, scientific, social reform, professional, business, educational, and other organizations.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
The Germany. Deutsche Kongress-Zentrale (DKZ) was founded in 1934, and since November 13, 1936, was subordinated to the Reichsministerium fur Volksaufklarung und Propaganda of the German government. The DKZ regulated all organizational congresses, conventions, and meetings taking place in Germany. It issued permits, set dates, and coordinated the meetings with congreses scheduled abroad. Most private, semi-official, or official organizations in which the German citizenry participated are represented in this collection. The records include correspondence, memoranda, pamphlets, conference proceedings, clippings, and other printed matter for the period between 1870 and 1943, relating to both German and international congresses and conferences in the field of politics, art and sciences, economics, social welfare, trade and industry, labor, and education.
Congresses and conventions.; Germany.; International agencies--Congresses.; International cooperation.
- Subject File, 1870-1943 (Box 1-349)
  Scope and Contents note
  - Abolitionistenverband (Box 1)
  - Abstinenzlerbewegungen
  - Abwasserwesen, 1938
  - Academic societies publications, 1879-1939
  - Academies, Association Internationale des, 1918 (Box 2)
  - Acetylen (VI-IX Kongresse), 1908-1913, 1923-1927, 1930-1942
  - Administration of Togo, 1935 (Box 3)
  - Adressbuch-Verleger, 1939
  - Adressen, Medizinische, 1935-1938
  - Adventisten, Siebenten-Tags-, 1939
  - Aero-Club de France, undated
  - Aerologische Kommission Internationale, 1939-1941
  - Aeronautik, Office Internationale Dokumentation, 1934-1939
  - Aeronautik, Internationale Federation, 1938-1942
  - Aeronautik, Internationaler Kongress, 1913-1914
  - Aerzte, Franzoesische, 1935-1936
  - Aerzte-Kongress, 1938-1939
  - Aerzte-Kongress, Katholischer, 1936-1938
  - Aerzte-Kongress, Panamerikanischer, 1937
  - Aerzte-Kongress in Tokio, 1942
  - Aerzte und Seelsorger, 1938
  - Aerzte, Wien, 1937 (Box 4)
  - Aerztebund, Nationalsozialistischer Deutscher, 1934-1937
  - Aerztefuehrer, Reichs-, 1937
  - Aerztegesellschaft, Schwedische, undated
  - Aerztekammer, Niederlaendishce, 1942
  - Aerzte, Mechano-therapeutische, 1927-1941
  - Aerztetag, 1939
  - Aerztetagung, Alpenlaendische, 1939
  - Aerztliche Fortbildung, Akademie fuer, 1940
  - Aerztliches Fortbildungswesen, 1937
  - Aerztinnen-Kongress, 1942
  - Aerztliche Mission, Verein fuer, 1936
  - Aesthetik und Kunstwissenschaft, 1937
  - Affairs, Britisch Institute of International, 1921 (Box 5)
  - Afrikanische Gesellschaft in Deutschland, 1942
  - Afrikanische Sprachen und Kulturen, 1939-1941
  - Agrarkreditkonferenzen, Internationale, 1933-1938
  - Agrarsozialer Kongress, 1939
  - Agrarwissenschaft, Internationale Konferenz fuer, 1938
  - Agriculture, 1912
  - Agriculture des Pays Chauds, 1939
  - Agriculture, Confederation Internationale de l', 1937-1942
  - Agriculture Co-ordination, 1941 (Box 6)
  - "Ahnenerbe, ", 1939
  - Aircraft Standards Commission International, 1942
  - Airtraffic Association, 1937-1942
  - Akademia, 1939
  - Akademie, Deutsche, 1939
  - Akademie, Deutsche, der Dichtung, undated
  - Akademie fuer aerztliche Fortbildung, 1939
  - Akademie fuer Deutsches Recht, 1940
  - Akademie fuer Indische Kultur, Internationale, 1938
  - Akademie, Deutsche, der Naturforscher, 1935-1937
  - Akademie der Wissenschaften, Preussische, 1938
  - Akademie, Pommersche, fuer Landesforschung, 1942
  - Akademia, Wissenschaftliches Korrespondenzbuero, October 25, 1938-December 1939 (Box 7)
  - Akademia, Wissenschaftliches Korrespondenzbuero, December 1939-June 1940 (Box 8)
  - Akademia, Wissenschaftliches Korrespondenzbuero, 1940-1941 (Box 9)
  - Akademia, Wissenschaftliches Korrespondenzbuero, 1941-1942 (Box 10)
  - Akademia, Wissenschaftliches Korrespondenzbuero, 1942-1943 (Box 11)
  - Akademia, Wissenschaftliches Korrespondenzbuero, 1943 (Box 12)
  - Akademikertgung, Deutsch-Schwedische, 1940 (Box 13)
  - Akademische Internationale, undated
  - Aktivisten, 1940
  - Akustik, 1937-1941
  - Alkohol, Internationale Katholische Liga gegen den, 1939-1941
  - Alkoholgefahren, 1938-1940
  - Alkoholgegner-Verband, Internationaler-Eisenbahn, 1942
  - Alkoholismus, undated
  - Alkoholismus, undated (Box 14)
  - Alkoholismus, Internationaler Verband zur Bekaempfung des, undated
  - Alkoholmissbrauch, 1939
  - Alkoholfreie Kultur, Deutscher Verein fuer, 1937-1942
  - Alkoholnot, Evangelishce Reichsarbeitsgemeinschaft zur Bekaempfung der, 1936
  - All People's Association, 1932
  - Allergische Krankheiten, 1940
  - Allgemeine und textile Marktwirtschaft, 1941
  - Alliance Francaise, 1932
  - Alliance Internationale de Tourisme, 1938
  - Alpenlaendische Aerztetagung, 1941 (Box 15)
  - Alpinistische Vereinigung, Internationale, 1941
  - Altenburger Papiermacher, 1940
  - Alterturmsforschung, 1940
  - Altveteranen, 1939
  - Aluminium, 1939
  - Amateurphotographe, 1938
  - Amateurphotograph, 1938
  - Amateurtanzen, 1939
  - Ambulantes Gewerbe, 1938
  - Ambulantes Gewerbe, 1937-1942
  - American Academy for Political and Social Science, 1938
  - Amerika-Werkstudenten, 1938-1939
  - Amerikanisten-Kongress, Internationaler, 1938-1939
  - Anatomische Gesellschaft, 1938
  - Amis de Louise-Luce Dantin, 1941 (Box 16)
  - Anaesthesie und Chirurgie, Allgemeiner Kongress fuer, 1939
  - Anatomen-Kongress, 1941
  - Ankra, 1939
  - Anarchisten-Kongress, Internationaler, 1905
  - Anesthesia Research Society, International, 1936
  - Anglo-amerikanische Musik-Konferenz, 1936
  - Antikomintern, 1937-1939
  - Antisemitismus und Rassismus, Internationale, Liga gegen der, 1938
  - Anthropologie, Kriminelle, 1896
  - Anthroposophisches Institut, 1942
  - Anthropologie, Internationaler Kongress fuer, 1938
  - Anthropologie, Internationales Institut fuer, 1937
  - Apocrypha International, Society of, 1905 (Box 17)
  - Apothekerbund, Internationaler, undated
  - Apothekerkammer, Reichs-, 1939
  - Apothekerkammer, Internationale, 1943
  - Apothekertag, Reichs-, 1940
  - Apothekertagung, 1938-1939
  - Apparatwesen, Chemisches, 1940
  - "Arbeit und Freude, " Weltkongress, 1938
  - Arbeitergaerten, Internationaler Kongress, 1912-1937 (Box 18)
  - Arbeiter, Intellektuelle, 1923-1927
  - Arbeiter, Internationale, 1923-1933
  - Arbeiterjugend, Christliche, 1941
  - Arbeiter der sozialistischen Industrie der UdSSR, 1941
  - Arbeiterbildungswesen, 1935-1936
  - Arbeitersport und Koerperkultur, 1913
  - Arbeiterverband, 1941
  - Arbeiterversicherung, 1940
  - Arbeiterversicherung, Kongresse fuer, 1889-1907
  - Arbeiterwelt, Kongress, 1940
  - Arbeiterwohnungen, 1910
  - Arbeitgeber, Katholische, 1941
  - Arbeitgeber, Internationale, 1938
  - Arbeitnehmerverbaende Evangelischer, 1928-1936
  - Arbeitnehmer Oeffentlicher Verwaltungen, 1930
  - Arbeitsaemter Grossdeutschlands, 1942 (Box 19)
  - Arbeitsamt Bruessel, undated
  - Arbeitsamt, Internationales, 1938-1939
  - Arbeitsdienst, 1938
  - Arbeitsdiensttagung, 1936
  - Arbeitskonferenz, 1940
  - Arbeitskongress Latein-amerikanischer, 1932
  - Arbeitslosenfuersorge, 1912
  - Arbeitslosigkeit, Internationale Vereingung zur Bekaemptung, 1909-1910
  - Arbeitsmedizin, Institut fuer, 1943 (Box 20)
  - Arbeits-Physiologie, 1933
  - Arbeitsrechtsprechung, 1910-1912
  - Arbeitschutz, 1897-1913, 1936, 1938
  - Arbeitstherapie, Institut fuer, undated
  - Arbeitsschutz, Reichsstelle fuer, undated
  - Arbeitszeitermittlung, 1924
  - Arbitrage, 1915
  - Arbitration, International, undated
  - Arboreteum, 1940
  - Archaelogen
  - Archaeologen, 1939 (Box 21)
  - Archaeologie, 1906-1939
  - Archaeologie, Griechische, 1939
  - Archaeologie, Christliche, 1938
  - Archeologie, Federation Archeologique et Historique, undated
  - Archaeologie, Praehistorische, 1934-1938
  - Architekten, 1935-1941
  - Architektenverbaende, Nationale, 1872-1920
  - Archivare, Vereinigung Deutscher Nichtstaatlicher, 1941 (Box 22)
  - Archivare und Altertumsverein, 1941
  - Archivwesen, Deutscher Tag Fuer, 1939
  - "Argus" Nachrichtenbuero, 1937
  - Arierforschung, 1939
  - Arktisforschung, Internationale Gesellschaft zur, mit Luftfahrzeugen, 1924-1929
  - Arpa, Internationale, 1939
  - Arpa (Arbeitsgemeinschaft fuer Paradentoseforschung), 1939-1940
  - Art Public, 1898
  - Artisten, 1940
  - Arts, des Lettres et des Sciences, Federation Internationale des, 1939-1941
  - Arts Populaires, Commission Internationale des, 1942
  - Association des grandes organisations nationales des voyages et tourisme, 1933 (Box 23)
  - Association Henri Capitant, 1939
  - "Asted, " Association suisse pour l'organisation du travail et de la documentation, 1912-1914
  - Astra-Hotel-Vereinigung, undated
  - Astrologen, 1936-1942
  - Astrologentagung, Deutsch, 1938
  - Astrologentagung, 1935-1937
  - Astronomische Gesellschaft, 1935-1939
  - Astronomisches Recheninstutut, 1935
  - Astronomishce Telegramme, Zentralbuero fuer, 1938
  - Astronomische Union, 1922-1938
  - Asylrecht, 1936
  - Atomgewichte, Internationaler Komitee fuer, 1941
  - Atmosphaeren, 1921-1927
  - Auditeurs de l'Academie de droit, 1939 (Box 24)
  - Aufklaerungsauschuss, 1935-1936
  - Augenoptikerhandwerk, undated
  - Augenaerzte, 1939
  - Ausgrabungskonferent, Internationale, 1937
  - Auslandsdeutschen, Reichstagung der, 1938-1939
  - Auslands, Tagung des Deutschen, 1939
  - Auslands-Institut, Stuttgart, 1935-1941
  - Aussenamt, Franzoesisches, undated
  - Aussenpolitik, Stadium der, 1934
  - Auskunftfragen Ausserdeutsche, 1941
  - Auskunftteiwesen, Internationales, 1941
  - Auslaendische Presse in Berlin, 1928
  - Auslaendischen Presse Italien in, Verband der, undated
  - Auslaendsaemter, Studentische, 1921-1922
  - Auslandsarbeiter, 1942
  - Auslandsklub, 1942
  - Auslandsjournalisten in Wien, Vereinigung der, 1942
  - Auslandswissenschaftliches Institut, Deutsches, undated
  - Aussendeutscher Wachenspiegel, 1920-1942 (Box 25)
  - Aussendeutscher Studentenbund, 1940
  - Ausstellung, San Francisco, 1915
  - Ausstellung, Gent, 1913 (Box 26)
  - Ausstellung, Charleroi, 1911
  - Ausstellungs-und Messeausschuss der Deutschen Wirtschaft, 1939
  - Austausch-Kraftstoffe, 1938, 1940
  - Austausch der Kinder, 1903
  - Automobil-und Flugtechnische Gesellschaft, 1940
  - Automobil-Ausstellung, 1938
  - Automobil Clubs, Interational, 1935, 1943
  - Automobil (Konstruktion, Statistik), 1937, 1942
  - Automobilkonstruktevre, 1938-1939
  - Autoren und Komponisten, 1934-1940
  - Autoren und Komponisten, 1926-1938 (Box 27)
    - Argentinien, 1937
    - Australien, 1932-1933
    - Aegypten, 1929
    - Belgien, 1934
    - Brasilien, 1936
    - Kanada, 1938
    - China, 1938
    - Chile, 1934-1938
    - Daenemark, undated
    - Deutschland, 1936
    - Frankreich, 1936 (Box 28)
    - Grossbritannien, 1930
    - Holland, 1934
    - Irak, undated
    - Italien, 1936
    - Japan, 1936
    - UdSSR, 1938 (Box 29)
    - U.S.A., 1930
    - Tschechoslowakei, 1930
    - Schweiz, 1936
    - Schweden, 1937
    - Spanien, 1933
    - Rumaenien, 1934
    - Portugal, 1933
    - Polen, 1938
    - Palestinien, undated
    - Jugoslavien, 1936
    - Oesterreich, undated
    - Lettland, 1938
    - Griechenland, 1930
    - Uruguay, 1934
  - Autorenkongress, 1936 (Box 30)
  - Autorenrechte, 1922
  - Autostrassen, 1932
  - Auswaertige Presse, 1941
  - Auswaertiges Amt, 1940
  - Auswanderer, 1937-1941
  - Avocats, Union Internationale des, 1927
  - Azetylen, 1939
  - Azetylenverein, Deutscher, 1938
  - Azetylen-Kongress, 1939 (Box 31)
  - Baeckerhandwerk, 1939-1940
  - Baeckereifachausstellung, 1933
  - Baeckerhandwerk, 1939
  - Baeckereiwesen, 1939
  - Baeder-und Klimaheilkunde, Gesellschaft fuer, 1937-1940
  - Baederkongress, 1938-1939
  - Baerdertag, 1939 (Box 32)
  - Baedetbetriebe, 1939
  - Baederwesen, 1937
  - Batiment Travaux publics, 1937
  - Bahnwesen, 1940 (Box 33)
  - Bakterienforschung, undated
  - Balkanique, Union medicale, 1936-1939
  - Balkanique, Federation, de Tourisme, ff, 1931
  - Baltimore-Anti-Nazi-Gesellschaft, 1936
  - Bandagisten- und Othopaedie-Mechaniker-Handwerk, 1936, 1939
  - Banken und Versicherungen, 1939
  - Bankiertagung, Paris, 1936-1937
  - Baptisten-Verband, Welt-, 1908, 1939
  - Baskenfreunde und -forschung, 1899
  - Basketball, 1942
  - "Bau, " Reichsarbeitstagung des Fachamtes, 1938
  - Brauerei und Maelzerei, 1940
  - Bau- und Holzarbeiter, 1929, 1937, 1941 (Box 34)
  - Bauarbeiter, Internationale, 1923
  - Bauern-Friedenskonferenz, 1938
  - Bauernfunk, Internationale Zeutralstelle fuer, 1936
  - Bauerntag, 1938-1939
  - Bauernverbaende, 1940
  - Bauforschung, Deutsche Akademie fuer, 1937-1940
  - Baugerwerbe, 1939
  - Baumessetagung, 1938
  - Baumrassen und Forstsaatgut, undated
  - Bausparkassen, Weltkongress fuer, 1939
  - Baumwollkongress, 1938-1942
  - Baupolizeibeamtentagung, 1939 (Box 35)
  - Bauwesen, Internationales, 1938, 1939
  - Bayreuther Bund, 1940
  - Bayreuther Festspiele, undated
  - Beamte, 1939
  - Beamte, Deutsche, 1939
  - Beamten-Genossenschaftstag, 1939
  - Beamten-Genossenschaftsverband, 1938
  - Behaelter, Buero-, undated
  - Behausung, Internationaler Verband fuer, 1913
  - Beherbergungsgewerk, 1939
  - Behring-, Emil-, Archiv, 1940 (Box 36)
  - Behring, Marburg, 1940
  - Behring-Feier, 1940
  - "Bekleidung und Leder" (DAF, Fachamt), 1939 (Box 37)
  - Bekleidungsarbeiter, 1934
  - Beleuchtungskommission, Internationale, 1935, 1939
  - Beleuchtungskongress, 1937
  - Belgian Archives, 1921
  - Benzol, 1929
  - Beratungsdienst, Technisch-wirtschaftlicher, 1940
  - Bergarbeiter, Christliche, 1930
  - Bergakademie Clausthal, 1935
  - Bergarbeiterverband, Internationaler, 1820 (Box 38)
  - "Bergbau, " Reichstagung, 1937-1939
  - Bergbau-Kongress, 1930-1938
  - Bergbau-Verein, 1938-1940
  - Bergbewohner, 1939
  - Bergmannstag, 1938
  - Bergsteigerverband, Deutscher, 1941
  - Berg- und Heuttenbau, 1938
  - Berichterstattung, Internationaler Verband fuer, 1941
  - Berichterstattung, Reichzentrale fuer Wissenschaftliche, 1941
  - Berliner Fremdenverkehrsverein, 1937
  - Berliner Freunde, 1938
  - Berufsausbildung, 1939
  - Berufsboxer, 1942
  - Berufliches Bildungswesen, 1938 (Box 39)
  - Berufserziehung, 1939 (Box 40)
  - Berufskrankheiten, Internationaler Kongress fuer, undated
  - Berufslenkung fuer Wallonien, undated
  - Berufsnachwuch, undated
  - Berufsvereinigung der Aerzte, Internationale, undated
  - Berufswettkampf, 1939
  - Beschaffungswesen, 1939
  - Bestgestaltung der Arbeit in Betrieben, 1941
  - Beton, 1942
  - Betriebsaerzte, 1939
  - Betriebsgestaltung, 1939
  - Betriebsingenieure, 1939
  - Betriebslehre, Institut fuer, undated
  - Betriebsschutz, 1939
  - Betriebswirte, 1939
  - Betriebswirtschaft, 1940
  - Betriebswirtschaft des Fremdenverkehrs, Institut fuer, 1941
  - Betriebswirtschaftertag, 1939-1940 (Box 41)
  - Betriebswissenschaftliche, Tagung, 1940
  - Bevoelkerungswissenschaftlicher Kongress, 1925
  - Bewachungsgesellschaft, Internationale, undated
  - Bibelforscher, undated
  - Bibliographie, Institut fuer internationale wissenschaftliche, 1910-1942
  - Bibliographie, Institut International de, ff., 1908
  - Bibliographie, Internationale, ff., 1908 (Box 42)
  - Bibliographie, Gesellschaft der Internationaler, zu Weimer, 1940 (Box 43)
  - Bibliophilen, Gesellschaft der, 1936-1937
  - Bibliothekare, Landwritschaftliche, undated
  - Bibliothekare, Verein Deutscher, 1938-1939
  - Bibliothekartag, 1938
  - Bibliothekarvereine, Internationaler Verband der, 1929-1936
  - Bibliothekshinweise, undated
  - Bibliotheque Collective, undated
  - Biboa, 1926-1942 (Box 44)
  - Bienenzucht, Internationale Kongresse fuer, 1897-1939
  - Bienenwirte, 1938
  - Bildenden Kuenste, Reichskammer der, 1938-1939 (Box 45)
  - Bildhauer, 1939
  - Bildstellen, 1939
  - Bildungsarbeiter, 1922-1935
  - Bildungswesen, 1938
  - Bildungswesen, Kaufmaennisches, 1901-1938
  - Binnenhafenkonferenzen, Internationale, undated
  - Binnenschiffahrt, 1934-1936
  - Binneschiffahrtstag, 1938-1940
  - Biochemie
  - Biologie, Allgemein
  - Biologie d. Grosstadt, Konferenz fuer medizinische wissenschaftliche Zusammenarbeit
  - Biologie, Konferenzen u. Kongresse
  - Biologische Anstalt, Helgoland
  - Biologie, Reichsbund fuer, 1939 (Box 46)
  - Biologischen Wissenschaften, Internationale Union der, 1935-1942
  - Biologen, Deutsche, 1919-1931
  - Biologische Reichsanstalt fuer Land- und Forstwirtschaft, 1935
  - Biologische Standardisierung, 1941
  - Bitument, 1937
  - Blaues Kreuz, 1937
  - Blinden, Internationale Vereinigung der, 1929
  - Blindheitsverhuetung, 1929-1942
  - Bluttransfustion, 1935-1937
  - Bob, 1923
  - Bodenkundliche Gesellschaft, 1939
  - Bodenchemiekongress, 1932 (Box 47)
  - Bodenkunde, Europaeische Arbeitsgemeinschaft fuer, 1942
  - Bodenkundliche Gesellschaft, 1940
  - Bodenmechanik und Grundbau, 1936
  - Bodenregulierung, undated
  - Boeke-Konferenz, 1926-1938
  - Boersenverein der Deutschen Buchhaendler, 1937
  - Boersenverein, 1940
  - Bohrtechniker, 1942
  - Bohrungs-Ingenieure, 1939
  - Bookbinders and Bibliographies, International, 1913
  - Botanik, Gartenbau, 1864-1892
  - Botanique, Office Internationale (Box 48)
  - Botanische Gesellschaft, Deutsche, 1938-1941
  - Botanischer Kongress, Internationaler, undated
  - Betonverein, 1939
  - Boxen, 1921-1937
  - Boxkongress, 1938
  - Brasserie, Societe Internationale de, undated
  - Brauerei-Kongress, 1935-1942
  - Brauereiarbeiter, 1910
  - Brauerei- und Maelzerhandwerk, 1939 (Box 49)
  - Braunkolenbergbau, 1939
  - Braunkohlen-Industrie-Verein, Deutshcer, 1938
  - "Bremen-Schluessel zur Welt, " Ausstellung, 1938
  - Brunnenbau, 1938
  - Breslauer Messe, 1940
  - Betriebswirtschaftertag, 1938
  - Briefmarken, 1942
  - Briefmarkenhaendlertagung, 1938-1939
  - Brieftauben-Ausstellung, 1939
  - Brieftaubenzuechter-Kongress, 1938-1939
    - Printed material
    - Correspondence (Box 50)
  - Briefwechsel, Bruessel, 1941-1942
  - Brigadetreffen, 1939
  - British Colonies, 1910-1920
  - British Council, undated
  - British Medical Journal, 1942
  - Broadcasting, Washington, 1939
  - Brotfabrikenverband, Internationaler, 1935-1936
  - Brotindustrie, undated
  - "Bruecke, Die, " Internationale Institut, 1920
  - Bruecken- und Hochbau, 1936 (Box 51)
  - Bruechen- und Hochbau, Internationale Vereinigung fuer, 1929-1936
  - Brucknergemeinschaft, Internationale, 1939
  - Buchausstellung, 1935-1942
  - Buchbinder-Foederation, Internationale, 1907
  - Buchbinderhandwerk, 1938-1939 (Box 52)
  - Buchdruckereibesitzer, Kongress der, 1940
  - Buchdruckerverein, Deutscher, 1938-1940
  - Buchgewerbe und Graphik, 1914
  - Buchhandel, 1939
  - Buchhandel-Verlag, 1940
  - Buchhandels-Gesellschaft, 1911-1912
  - Buchhaltungskongress, Internationaler, 1939
  - Buchhaltungswoche, 1937-1938
  - Bude, Societe Guillaume, undated
  - Buehnentechnische Gesellschaft, Deutsche, 1939
  - Buehnenverleger, undated
  - Bulgarishces Wissenschaftliches Institut, 1942
  - Bund Persoenlichter Freundschaft mit Auslaendern, undated
  - (BPA), 1941-1942
  - Bunker-Kohle, 1942
  - Bunsen-Gesellschaft, 1936-1941
  - Bunsen-Gesellschaft, 1936-1941 (Box 53)
  - Bureau of International Affairs, 1907
  - Byzantisten, 1924-1936
  - Calvinisten, 1932-1938
  - Calwer Handelsschueler, 1939
  - Caritas-Verband, undated
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1915-1930
  - Casa de America, 1920 (Box 54)
  - Centre Germano-Espanol, undated
  - Centre, International, undated
  - Centre, International, Bruxelles, undated
  - Chemie, Buero fuer reine und angevandte, undated
  - Chemie, Bureau fuer internationale, 1932-1936
  - Chemie-Gesellschaft, undated
  - Chemie-Ingenieure, 1936-1940
  - Chemie, Internationale Union Fuer, 1920-1936
  - Chemieanalyst, 1910-1923
  - Chemie, Augewandte, 1894-1912
  - Chemiedozenten, Nordwestdeutsche, 1939 (Box 55)
  - Chemiker, Deutsche, 1937-1943
  - Chemiker-Coloristen, 1937-1939
  - Chemiker-Coloristen, 1937-1939 (Box 56)
  - Chemiker, Verein Deutscher, undated
  - Chemisches Apparatewesen, 1939 (Box 57)
  - "Chevaliers du Prince de la Paix, ", 1941
  - China, 1907-1911
  - Chinese Medical Association, 1933-1937
  - Chinesische Studenten in Europe, 1934-1936
  - Chiropractic, European Union, 1938
  - Chirurgen, Vereinigung Mitteldeutscher, 1939
  - Chirurgen, Vereinigung Bayrischer, 1939
  - Chirurgen-Kollegium, Internationales, 1937-1939
  - Chirurgen-Kongress, 1938-1939
  - Chirurgen-Gesellschaft, Mittelrheninsche, undated
  - Chirurgen, Tagung Nordwestdeutscher, in Danzig, 1938
  - Chirurgie, 1939
  - Chirurgie (Allgemein), 1939
  - Chirurgie, Deutsche Gesellschaft fuer, 1938-1940
  - Chirurgie, Deutsche Gesellschaft fuer, 1938-1940 (Box 58)
  - Chirurgie, Internationale, 1936-1942
  - Chirurgie, Kriegs-, 1942
  - Chirurgie, Society of British Neurological, 1937
  - Chirurgie, Struktive (Plastische), 1937-1939
  - Chirurgenvereinigung, 1939
  - Cholera, 1940
  - Chormusik, 1939
  - Christentum, 1939
  - Christian Science, undated
  - Christian German Refugees, 1937
  - Christkoenig-Kongress, 1937-1939
  - Chromersatz-Karton, 1935
  - Cinematographe, 1942
  - Cites Lineaires, 1942 (Box 59)
  - Cobden Club, 1908-1910
  - Coca-Cola G.m.b.H., 1939
  - Colonialism, 1896-1929
  - Comite Interallie, 1920
  - Commerce, Developpement et Protection, 1942
  - Commerce/Industry, 1830-1913
  - Commerce/Industry, undated (Box 60)
  - Commisstion de Legislature, 1937
  - Communications, 1913 (Box 61)
  - Comptabilite, 1910-1937
  - Conciliation, International, undated
  - Conciliation, International, 1913-1932 (Box 62)
  - Conciliation, International, 1913-1932 (Box 63)
  - Confederation Internationale des Etudiants, 1919-1938
  - Confederation Internationale des Etudiants, 1919-1938 (Box 64)
  - Congres Mondia Association des Internationales, 1908-1910 (Box 65)
  - Congres Penitentiaire International, 1900
  - Congres des Patronages, 1911 (Box 66)
  - Congres des Sciences Administrative, undated
  - Congres Mondial des Associations Internationales, undated
  - Congres Mondial des Associations Internationales, undated (Box 67)
  - Conseil International de Recherches
  - Cooperation Intellectuelle, 1926-1937
  - Cooperation Intellectuelle, 1926-1937 (Box 68)
  - "Corda Fratres, " Federation Internationale des Etudiant, 1898
  - Correspondence Mensuelle, 1912
  - Credit populaire, undated
  - Cytologie, undated
  - DAAD, Kulturpolitische Nachrichten, 1939-1941 (Box 69)
  - Daenische Kongress-Zentrale, 1942
  - Damenschneiderhandwerks, 1939
  - Dampfapparaten, Internationaler Verband zur Ueberwachung und Sicherung von, 1910-1917